<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>agile on Transparency, Inspection, and Adaptation</title>
    <link>bforrest.com/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in agile on Transparency, Inspection, and Adaptation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="bforrest.com/tags/agile/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Act of Transforming</title>
      <link>bforrest.com/post/2018-08-08-the-act-of-transforming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bforrest.com/post/2018-08-08-the-act-of-transforming/</guid>
      <description>What does transformation mean for an organization of people? Organizations treat an agile transformation as a singular event. It is a budgetary line item, a noun, a one-time metamorphosis from caterpillar to butterfly. Expert agilists who have “been there, done that” are sought to guide the transformation. While one gains credibility by having “been there, done that,” what impact does that have on our vision? How does this distort our ability to be empathetic?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brewing Great Agile Team Dynamics</title>
      <link>bforrest.com/post/2017-03-01-brewing-great-agile-team-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bforrest.com/post/2017-03-01-brewing-great-agile-team-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Ever find yourself making a sour face after talking to a coworker?
Wishing your team meetings felt more like an engaging social hour?
There is hope. Those everyday conflicts where something seems “off” after a conversation are often related to differences in communication styles. When team members understand themselves and others, there’s less conflict, more collaboration, and better working relationships.
The DiSC model can help you understand why your team behaves the way it does and how to build trust for a more agile team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
