<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>team dynamics on Transparency, Inspection, and Adaptation</title>
    <link>https://bforrest.com/tags/team-dynamics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in team dynamics on Transparency, Inspection, and Adaptation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bforrest.com/tags/team-dynamics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forbidden Island Team Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://bforrest.com/post/2019-06-11-forbidden-island-team-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bforrest.com/post/2019-06-11-forbidden-island-team-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>While at The Path to Agility 2019, I had the pleasure of attending Team Dynamics on the Forbidden Island, hosted by Paul Boos . This session used a co-operative table-top game, Forbidden Island to explore team dynamics and illustrate Tuckman’s stages of group development- “storming, forming, norming, performing&amp;quot;
Here’s the publisher’s description of the game:
Join a team of fearless adventurers on a do-or-die mission to capture four sacred treasures from the ruins of this perilous paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was It Worth It?</title>
      <link>https://bforrest.com/post/2018-01-02-was-it-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bforrest.com/post/2018-01-02-was-it-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>A few of us from the office headed out to an acclaimed BBQ joint during the holiday lull between Christmas and New Years. I expected the last workday of the year to be slow with a bunch of the workforce out on vacation. Boy was I wrong.
When we arrived, the line snaked from the cash register, around all of the picnic tables and looped back upon itself once without making anyone wait in the cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brewing Great Agile Team Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://bforrest.com/post/2017-03-01-brewing-great-agile-team-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bforrest.com/post/2017-03-01-brewing-great-agile-team-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Ever find yourself making a sour face after talking to a coworker?
Wishing your team meetings felt more like an engaging social hour?
There is hope. Those everyday conflicts where something seems “off” after a conversation are often related to differences in communication styles. When team members understand themselves and others, there’s less conflict, more collaboration, and better working relationships.
The DiSC model can help you understand why your team behaves the way it does and how to build trust for a more agile team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
